<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">
<channel>
        <title>Smith Suth</title>
        <description>Smith Suth - Smith Suth</description>
        <link>http://mcsuth.github.io</link>
        <link>http://mcsuth.github.io</link>
        <lastBuildDate>2014-09-15T18:55:59-07:00</lastBuildDate>
        <pubDate>2014-09-15T18:55:59-07:00</pubDate>
        <ttl>1800</ttl>


        <item>
                <title>First Jekyll Post</title>
                <description>&lt;p&gt;Read &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllbootstrap.com/usage/jekyll-quick-start.html&quot;&gt;Jekyll Quick Start&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Complete usage and documentation available at: &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllbootstrap.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;update-author-attributes&quot;&gt;Update Author Attributes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In &lt;code&gt;_config.yml&lt;/code&gt; remember to specify your own data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;title : My Blog =)

author :
  name : Name Lastname
  email : blah@email.test
  github : username
  twitter : username
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme should reference these variables whenever needed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;sample-posts&quot;&gt;Sample Posts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog contains sample posts which help stage pages and blog data.
When you don’t need the samples anymore just delete the &lt;code&gt;_posts/core-samples&lt;/code&gt; folder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ rm -rf _posts/core-samples
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a sample “posts list”.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://mcsuth.github.io/2014/09/04/hola-world</link>
                <guid>http://mcsuth.github.io/2014/09/04/hola-world</guid>
                <pubDate>2014-09-04T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Recursive Ruby   Factorials</title>
                <description>
&lt;pre&gt;
~ def factorial(n)
~   if n == 0
~     1
~   else
~     n * factorial(n - 1)
~   end
~ end
~ factorial(5) // 120
&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://mcsuth.github.io/solution/2013/12/13/recursive-ruby---factorials</link>
                <guid>http://mcsuth.github.io/solution/2013/12/13/recursive-ruby---factorials</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-12-13T00:00:00-08:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Last Day of Work in Boston</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;Today is officially my last day at BII. I’m ready for something new. I have no idea what San Francisco holds for me, but all I know is that relocating from Boston to San Francisco with no concrete plan and a few quarters in my pocket is a huge risk that I will be undertaking. I understand the risks, but you know what they say: Big Risk = Big Reward… or was it Big Loss…?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://mcsuth.github.io/life/2013/08/15/last-day-of-work-in-boston</link>
                <guid>http://mcsuth.github.io/life/2013/08/15/last-day-of-work-in-boston</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-08-15T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Work and the Stress</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;I’m excited to be finishing up with my job this week as I will have free time to devote to studying before I move myself across the country. As of right now, I find it extremely difficult to allocate some time to devote to my personal project because of everyday life. My only free time is the weekend, but I always end up getting some sort of distraction. I.E. My mother likes to visit me and sleep for hours at my place… If there aren’t distractions, I end up getting allergies of some sort or something! I.E. I’ve got allergies right now!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah yes, allergies. Yesterday I devoted the day to cleaning and pre-packing my life away. I guess I stirred up all the dust in my room and now I’ve got the runny nose and congestion like non other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other stressors in my life: How to break the news to the family that I’m moving and how to see all of my close friends before I move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So much to do, but so little time! I guess I like to operate like this. If things don’t get done with a bang, then things won’t get done.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peace, foolios!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://mcsuth.github.io/life/2013/08/11/work-and-the-stress</link>
                <guid>http://mcsuth.github.io/life/2013/08/11/work-and-the-stress</guid>
                <pubDate>2013-08-11T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
        </item>

        <item>
                <title>Hello World</title>
                <description>
&lt;p&gt;Hi Y’all,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just registered a domain in pursuit of starting my portfolio. When I registered the domain and began writing my website, I began to get nervous about my time constraints. Right now I’m following an individual who is creating a JavaScript website every day. It’s crazy and fantastic. However, how does she find the time to do it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t wait for the last day of my job because I will be able to devote time to study before I leave to San Fran at the end of August.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned y’all. Things are going to happen.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
                <link>http://mcsuth.github.io/life/2012/09/04/hello-world</link>
                <guid>http://mcsuth.github.io/life/2012/09/04/hello-world</guid>
                <pubDate>2012-09-04T00:00:00-07:00</pubDate>
        </item>


</channel>
</rss>
